{
    "id": "861dbc1534a242f89787e559e7eac2a2",
    "title": "English vocabulary worksheet | Gap fills",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "8b0a32df10bd48bba1102fbce9c75503",
            "title": "English vocabulary quiz",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "She always …………………. to her elder sister.",
                    "description": "To defer is to give in to someone",
                    "answers": [
                        "defers",
                        "deflects",
                        "defaces"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "May I return this toaster if it is .....................…?",
                    "description": "If something is defective, it is faulty.",
                    "answers": [
                        "deflective",
                        "defective",
                        "deferential"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The policeman’s badge ...................... the bullet.",
                    "description": "To deflect is to prevent something undesirable from being aimed at you. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "defaced",
                        "deduced",
                        "deflected"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "His treatment of the elderly people was affectionate and .....................",
                    "description": "Deferential means respectful.",
                    "answers": [
                        "defiance",
                        "deferential",
                        "defunct"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "She has a ..................... that makes walking difficult.",
                    "description": "Deformity means a malformation.",
                    "answers": [
                        "defiance",
                        "deformity",
                        "deflection"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "After all those expenses, we ended the year with a ......................",
                    "description": "Deficit means an excess of money spent over money earned.",
                    "answers": [
                        "deficit",
                        "decorum",
                        "deference"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The company has been ..................... since the war.",
                    "description": "If something is defunct it is no longer functioning.",
                    "answers": [
                        "defunct",
                        "deferential",
                        "deflective"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ………………… the book by writing on it.",
                    "description": "To deface is to spoil the appearance of something.",
                    "answers": [
                        "decorated",
                        "defered",
                        "defaced"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The child showed ..................... by refusing to eat.",
                    "description": "Defiance means open refusal to obey.",
                    "answers": [
                        "reluctance",
                        "defiance",
                        "decorum"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "From her conversation, I ...................... that she had a large family.",
                    "description": "To deduce is to form an opinion or conclusion.",
                    "answers": [
                        "defered",
                        "deflected",
                        "deduced"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ………………… it advisable to buy property now.",
                    "description": "To deem is to consider something in a particular way.",
                    "answers": [
                        "deter",
                        "deem",
                        "denounce"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Jennifer always acts with ......................",
                    "description": "Decorum means polite and socially acceptable behavior.",
                    "answers": [
                        "defunct",
                        "deferential",
                        "decorum"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}